Candice Haddad

Software Engineer

Phone 317-985-8281 LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/candicehaddad/

I firmly believe that software and technology can and does make significant impacts on people's quality of life. As an academic researcher turned developer, I build meaningful, rich software that emphasizes accessibility, empathy, and usability for users and engineers alike.

Experience

2015-08 - present Software Engineer

Jellyvision, Inc

- develop and maintain software solutions across the stack using Javascript and Ruby
- built from the ground up authoring tool and frontend experience, updating our architecture to use HTML5, React, and Redux
- led major refactor effort on frontend and backend of customer-facing user analytics and data application
- contribute to design and development of multiple internal RESTful APIs
- mentor and sponsor junior software engineers
- participate in diversity and inclusion hiring and retention efforts

2015-02 - 2015-06 Software Development Student

Dev Bootcamp

- learned software development skills during a 19-week immersive program
- developed a mobile-first web application using Ruby on Rails and Javascript (AJAX, JQuery)
- developed a crisis response web application using Ruby and Sinatra
- learned Agile best practices

2012-08 - 2015-01 Ph.D. Researcher

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

- conducted ethnographic research on how Arab American youth consume and produce digital media
- collected and analyzed qualitative data for dissertation project

2010-09 - 2015-01 Graduate Student Instructor

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

- assisted instruction on courses concerning media, culture, and society
- led and designed courses on Internet cultures and networks; digital media and identity.

Education

2009 - 2014	University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

PhD, Communication Studies

2007 - 2009 University of Texas, Austin

MA, Media Studies

2002 - 2006 Indiana University, Bloomington

BA, Communication and Culture, minor in French

Additional Activities

2015 BLUE1647

Ruby Instructor

2014 - 2016 Women Who Code

Chicago Chapter Co-Founder/ Director

2016 Chi Ladies Hack

Co-Organizer

Skills

Javascript (including ES6+)

React (Redux)

HTML5

CSS

Ruby (including Rails, Grape, Sinatra)

Relational databases (MySQL, SQLite, Postgres)

AWS (Cognito, ECS, Elastic Beanstalk, and more)

Redis

Git

Agile development

Test-driven development

Pair programming

Mentoring

Teaching